[{"stepName": "Identify Motion of objects", "stepNumber": 1, "stepQuestions": [{"question": "How many moving objects are present?", "options": [1, 5, 0, 2], "answer": 3, "threejsstep": "motion", "threejssubstep": 0, "threejssubsubstep": -1, "show1": [""], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081p, a\u2082"], "showfc": [], "showfcheading": []}, {"question": "How many strings are there?", "options": [4, 1, 3, 2], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "motion", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 0, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081p, a\u2082"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081p, a\u2082, T\u2081, "], "showfc": [], "showfcheading": []}, {"question": "How many contacting surfaces are there?", "options": [0, 3, 1, 4], "answer": 2, "threejsstep": "motion", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": 0, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081p, a\u2082, T\u2081"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081p, a\u2082, T\u2081, "], "showfc": [], "showfcheading": []}]}, {"stepName": "Write FBD equation for each Moving block", "stepNumber": 2, "stepQuestions": [{"question": "How many surfaces are in contact with the red block?", "options": [4, 1, 2, 3], "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": -200, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081p, a\u2082, T\u2081, "], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081p, a\u2082, T\u2081, "], "answer": 1, "showfc": ["Upward Perpendicular Forces: ", "Downward Perpendicular Forces: ", "Forces up the incline: ", "Forces down the incline: "], "showfcheading": ["Red block"]}, {"question": "What is the direction of normal reaction on block 1 due to B?", "options": ["N1 perpendicular up", "N1 perpendicular down"], "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 1, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081p, a\u2082, T\u2081, "], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081p, a\u2082, T\u2081, "], "answer": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Perpendicular Forces: ", "Downward Perpendicular Forces: ", "Forces up the incline: ", "Forces down the incline: "], "showfcheading": ["Red block"]}, {"question": "At how many points does the imaginary sphere for red block cuts the strings", "options": [0, 1, 2, 3], "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": -100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081p, a\u2082, T\u2081, "], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081p, a\u2082, T\u2081, "], "showfc": ["Upward Perpendicular Forces: ", "Downward Perpendicular Forces: ", "Forces up the incline: ", "Forces down the incline: "], "showfcheading": ["Red block"], "answer": 1}, {"question": "What is the force at this point of intersection on red block?", "options": ["T\u2081 down the incline ", "T\u2081 up the incline "], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 2, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081p, a\u2082, T\u2081, "], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081p, a\u2082, T\u2081, "], "showfc": ["Upward Perpendicular Forces: ", "Downward Perpendicular Forces: ", "Forces up the incline: ", "Forces down the incline: "], "showfcheading": ["Red block"]}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of red block along the incline?", "options": ["+T\u2081+30sin(45)=3.0a\u2081p", "-T\u2081+30sin(45)=3.0a\u2081p", "+T\u2081-30sin(45)=3.0a\u2081p", "-T\u2081-30sin(45)=3.0a\u2081p"], "answer": 2, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081p, a\u2082, T\u2081, "], "showfc": ["Upward Perpendicular Forces: N1, ", "Downward Perpendicular Forces: 30cos(45)", "Forces up the incline: T\u2081, ", "Forces down the incline: 30sin(45)"], "showfcheading": ["Red block"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081p, a\u2082, T\u2081, ", "+T\u2081-30sin(45)=3.0a\u2081p"]}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of red block perpendicular to the incline?", "options": ["+N\u2081+30cos(45)=0", "+N\u2081-30cos(45)=0", "-N\u2081+30cos(45)=0", "-N\u2081-30cos(45)=0"], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081p, a\u2082, T\u2081, ", "+T\u2081-30sin(45)=3.0a\u2081p"], "showfc": ["Upward Perpendicular Forces: N1, ", "Downward Perpendicular Forces: 30cos(45)", "Forces up the incline: T\u2081, ", "Forces down the incline: 30sin(45)"], "showfcheading": ["Red block"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081p, a\u2082, T\u2081, ", "+T\u2081-30sin(45)=3.0a\u2081p", "+N\u2081-30cos(45)=0"]}, {"question": "At how many points does the imaginary sphere for yellow block cuts the strings", "options": [0, 1, 2, 3], "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": -100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081p, a\u2082, T\u2081, ", "+T\u2081-30sin(45)=3.0a\u2081p", "+N\u2081-30cos(45)=0"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081p, a\u2082, T\u2081, ", "+T\u2081-30sin(45)=3.0a\u2081p", "+N\u2081-30cos(45)=0"], "showfc": ["Upward Forces: ", "Downward Forces: ", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Yellow block"], "answer": 1}, {"question": "What is the force at this point of intersection on yellow block?", "options": ["T\u2081 downwards", "T\u2081 upwards"], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": 1, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081p, a\u2082, T\u2081, ", "+T\u2081-30sin(45)=3.0a\u2081p", "+N\u2081-30cos(45)=0"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081p, a\u2082, T\u2081, ", "+T\u2081-30sin(45)=3.0a\u2081p", "+N\u2081-30cos(45)=0"], "showfc": ["Upward Forces: ", "Downward Forces: ", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Yellow block"]}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of yellow block in the y-direction", "options": ["+40+T\u2081=4.0a\u2082", "-40-T\u2081=4.0a\u2082", "-40+T\u2081=4.0a\u2082", "+40-T\u2081=4.0a\u2082"], "answer": 3, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": 100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081p, a\u2082, T\u2081, ", "+T\u2081-30sin(45)=3.0a\u2081p", "+N\u2081-30cos(45)=0"], "showfc": ["Upward Forces: T\u2081, ", "Downward Forces: 40", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Yellow block"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081p, a\u2082, T\u2081, ", "+T\u2081-30sin(45)=3.0a\u2081p", "+N\u2081-30cos(45)=0", "+40-T\u2081=4.0a\u2082"]}]}, {"stepName": "Constraint Understanding", "stepNumber": 3, "stepQuestions": [{"question": "What is the rate of change of the length of string if the dog is moving towards right with speed 5 m/s", "options": [-5, 5], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": [0, 5], "show1": [], "show2": ["Rate of change of length of the string is 5 m/s"], "showfc": [], "showfcheading": []}, {"question": "What is the rate of change of the length of string if the dog is moving towards left with speed 5 m/s", "options": [5, -5], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": [0, -5], "show1": [], "show2": ["Rate of change of length of the string is -5 m/s"], "showfc": [], "showfcheading": []}, {"question": "What is the rate of change of the length of string if the human is moving towards right with speed 3 m/s", "options": [-3, 3], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding", "threejssubstep": 3, "threejssubsubstep": [3, 0], "show1": [], "show2": ["Rate of change of length of the string is -3 m/s"], "showfc": [], "showfcheading": []}, {"question": "What is the rate of change of the length of string if the human is moving towards left with speed 3 m/s", "options": [-3, 3], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding", "threejssubstep": 4, "threejssubsubstep": [-3, 0], "show1": [], "show2": ["Rate of change of length of the string is 3 m/s"], "showfc": [], "showfcheading": []}, {"question": "What is the rate of change of the length of string only due to motion of dog in right direction with speed 5 m/s", "options": [5, -5], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding", "threejssubstep": 5, "threejssubsubstep": [3, 5], "show1": [], "show2": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is 5 m/s"], "showfc": [], "showfcheading": []}, {"question": "What is the rate of change of the length of string only due to motion of human in right direction with speed 3 m/s", "options": [3, -3], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding", "threejssubstep": 6, "threejssubsubstep": [3, 5], "show1": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is 5 m/s"], "show2": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is 5 m/s", "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of huamn is -3 m/s"], "showfc": [], "showfcheading": []}, {"question": "Net rate of change of length due to dog moving towards right direction with speed 5 m/s  and human moving in right direction with speed 3 m/s", "options": [2, -8, 8, -2], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding", "threejssubstep": 7, "threejssubsubstep": [3, 5], "show1": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is 5 m/s", "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of huamn is -3 m/s"], "show2": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is 5 m/s", "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of huamn is -3 m/s", "Total Rate of change of length of the string due motion of both human and dog is 2m/s"], "showfc": [], "showfcheading": []}, {"question": "What is the rate of change of the length of string only due to motion of dog in right direction with speed 5 m/s", "options": [-5, 5], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding", "threejssubstep": 8, "threejssubsubstep": [-3, 5], "show1": [], "show2": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is 5 m/s"], "showfc": [], "showfcheading": []}, {"question": "What is the rate of change of the length of string only due to motion of human in left direction with speed 3 m/s", "options": [-3, 3], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding", "threejssubstep": 9, "threejssubsubstep": [-3, 5], "show1": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is 5 m/s"], "show2": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is 5 m/s", "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of huamn is 3 m/s"], "showfc": [], "showfcheading": []}, {"question": "Net rate of change of length due to dog moving towards right direction with speed 5 m/s  and human moving in left direction with speed 3 m/s", "options": [2, -8, 8, -2], "answer": 2, "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding", "threejssubstep": 10, "threejssubsubstep": [-3, 5], "show1": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is 5 m/s", "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of huamn is 3 m/s"], "show2": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is 5 m/s", "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of huamn is 3 m/s", "Total Rate of change of length of the string due motion of both human and dog is 8m/s"], "showfc": [], "showfcheading": []}, {"question": "What is the rate of change of the length of string only due to motion of dog in left direction with speed 5 m/s", "options": [5, -5], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding", "threejssubstep": 11, "threejssubsubstep": [3, -5], "show1": [], "show2": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is -5 m/s"], "showfc": [], "showfcheading": []}, {"question": "What is the rate of change of the length of string only due to motion of human in right direction with speed 3 m/s", "options": [-3, 3], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding", "threejssubstep": 12, "threejssubsubstep": [3, -5], "show1": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is -5 m/s"], "show2": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is -5 m/s", "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of huamn is -3 m/s"], "showfc": [], "showfcheading": []}, {"question": "Net rate of change of length due to dog moving towards left direction with speed 5 m/s  and human moving in right direction with speed 3 m/s", "options": [-8, -2, 2, 8], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding", "threejssubstep": 13, "threejssubsubstep": [3, -5], "show1": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is -5 m/s", "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of huamn is -3 m/s"], "show2": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is -5 m/s", "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of huamn is -3 m/s", "Total Rate of change of length of the string due motion of both human and dog is -8m/s"], "showfc": [], "showfcheading": []}, {"question": "What is the rate of change of the length of string only due to motion of dog in left direction with speed 5 m/s", "options": [-5, 5], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding", "threejssubstep": 14, "threejssubsubstep": [-3, -5], "show1": [], "show2": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is -5 m/s"], "showfc": [], "showfcheading": []}, {"question": "What is the rate of change of the length of string only due to motion of human in left direction with speed 3 m/s", "options": [-3, 3], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding", "threejssubstep": 15, "threejssubsubstep": [-3, -5], "show1": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is -5 m/s"], "show2": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is -5 m/s", "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of huamn is 3 m/s"], "showfc": [], "showfcheading": []}, {"question": "Net rate of change of length due to dog moving towards left direction with speed 5 m/s  and human moving in left direction with speed 3 m/s", "options": [2, -2, -8, 8], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding", "threejssubstep": 16, "threejssubsubstep": [-3, -5], "show1": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is -5 m/s", "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of huamn is 3 m/s"], "show2": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is -5 m/s", "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of huamn is 3 m/s", "Total Rate of change of length of the string due motion of both human and dog is -2m/s"], "showfc": [], "showfcheading": []}]}, {"stepName": "Constraint Equations", "stepNumber": 4, "stepQuestions": [{"question": "What is the number of parts which change length in the pink string?", "options": [5, 4, 2, 3], "answer": 2, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": -1, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081p, a\u2082, T\u2081, ", "+T\u2081-30sin(45)=3.0a\u2081p", "+N\u2081-30cos(45)=0", "+40-T\u2081=4.0a\u2082"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081p, a\u2082, T\u2081, ", "+T\u2081-30sin(45)=3.0a\u2081p", "+N\u2081-30cos(45)=0", "+40-T\u2081=4.0a\u2082"], "showfc": [], "showfcheading": ["Pink string"]}, {"question": "What is double derivative of change in l\u2081 for pink string:", "options": ["+a\u2081", "-a\u2081"], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 1, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081p, a\u2082, T\u2081, ", "+T\u2081-30sin(45)=3.0a\u2081p", "+N\u2081-30cos(45)=0", "+40-T\u2081=4.0a\u2082"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081p, a\u2082, T\u2081, ", "+T\u2081-30sin(45)=3.0a\u2081p", "+N\u2081-30cos(45)=0", "+40-T\u2081=4.0a\u2082"], "showfc": ["l\u2081 + l\u2082 = constant"], "showfcheading": ["Pink string"]}, {"question": "What is double derivative of change in l\u2082 for pink string:", "options": ["+a\u2082", "-a\u2082"], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": 2, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081p, a\u2082, T\u2081, ", "+T\u2081-30sin(45)=3.0a\u2081p", "+N\u2081-30cos(45)=0", "+40-T\u2081=4.0a\u2082"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081p, a\u2082, T\u2081, ", "+T\u2081-30sin(45)=3.0a\u2081p", "+N\u2081-30cos(45)=0", "+40-T\u2081=4.0a\u2082"], "showfc": ["l\u2081 + l\u2082 = constant"], "showfcheading": ["Pink string"]}, {"question": "What is the constraint equation for pink string?", "options": ["+a\u2081p+a\u2082=0", "+a\u2081p-a\u2082=0", "-a\u2081p+a\u2082=0", "-a\u2081p-a\u2082=0"], "answer": 2, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 300, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081p, a\u2082, T\u2081, ", "+T\u2081-30sin(45)=3.0a\u2081p", "+N\u2081-30cos(45)=0", "+40-T\u2081=4.0a\u2082"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081p, a\u2082, T\u2081, ", "+T\u2081-30sin(45)=3.0a\u2081p", "+N\u2081-30cos(45)=0", "+40-T\u2081=4.0a\u2082", "-a\u2081p+a\u2082=0"], "showfc": ["l\u2081 + l\u2082 = constant", "l\u2081'' = -a\u2081", "l\u2082'' = +a\u2082"], "showfcheading": ["Pink string"]}]}]